A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- The impact of public policy on higher education: the nature and scope of the Foundation's role (Reports 009751), 1976 (Box 401)
  Higher education and state; Education and state; Education, Higher
- The management to higher education resources (Reports 009752), 1975 (Box 401)
  Education, Higher
- Minority participation in American higher education: taking stock of progress and charting the course ahead (Reports 009753), 1978 (Box 401)
  5 p. + appendices.
  Minorities -- Education -- United States; Education (Higher) -- United States
- Minority representation in the professions: report no. 1 (Reports 009754), 1973 (Box 401)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Minorities -- Education -- United States
- National library developments (Reports 009755), 1978 (Box 401)
  Library science -- United States; Libraries -- United States
- Notes and reflections respecting HER's programmatic efforts to improve "University finance and management" (Reports 009756), 1975 (Box 401)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States
- Predictions for undergraduate education (Reports 009757), undated (Box 401)
- Puerto Rico: problems of college access (Reports 009758), 1972 (Box 401)
  Education, Higher -- Puerto Rico
- The push-pull of foundation dollars (Reports 009759), 1973 (Box 401)
  This report appeared in The College Board Review, Winter 1973-1974, No. 90.
- Recent programs in support of private college (Reports 009760), 1978 (Box 401)
  Statistical breakdown of FF support of private colleges.
  Private universities and colleges -- Finance; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Education, Higher -- Finance
- Recommended grantees in venture fund: Midwest (Reports 009761), 1973 (Box 401)
- Report of conversations in Washington, April 22-24, 1975: persons in federal government who were consulted (Reports 009762) (Box 401)
- Reshaping higher education's agenda to meet new opportunities (Reports 009763), 1977 (Box 401)
- Selected state associations of independent colleges and universities: Consultants' reports of funded projects and activities (Reports 009764), 1975 (Box 401)
- Strengthening graduate education and increasing the opportunities for American minorities (Reports 009765), 1977 (Box 401)
- Underrepresented minorities in higher education taking stock of progress and charting the course ahead (Reports 009766), 1978 (Box 401)
  Education, Higher; Minorities -- Education
- The unionization and governance of higher education (Reports 009767), undated (Box 401)
  Education, Higher; Labor unions and education
- Initial briefing in Lagos (Reports 009768), 1969 (Box 401)
  Discussions concerning the state of higher education in Africa.
  Education, Higher -- Africa
- Will the academy survive unionization? (Reports 009769), 1976 (Box 401)
  This report appeared in the February 1976 issue of Change magazine.
  Change magazine
- Agenda papers and questions: Ford Foundation Population Conference, April 1968. (Reports 009770) (Box 401)
  Pa68-322.
- Administration of the graduate fellowship program (Reports 009771), 1974 (Box 401)
  Education, Higher; Fellowship program
- Affirmative action: Bakke case (Reports 009772), 1978 (Box 401)
  Affirmative action programs in education; Education, Higher; Minorities -- Education, Higher
- Brainstorming at Asilomar: program ideas to increase female's participation in nontraditional fields of study and work (Reports 009773), 1981 (Box 401)
  Education, Higher; Women -- Education
- Budget review of minority individual awards programs (Reports 009774), 1974 (Box 401)
  8 p. + attachements.
- Comments on ways to relate Title III to an endowment funding plan (Reports 009775), 1976 (Box 401)
- Community college finance program (Reports 009776), 1977 (Box 401)
- A crisis for racial fairness (Reports 009777), 1977 (Box 401)
  First rough draft also included.
- Division of Education and Research budget alternatives for FY 1978 (Reports 009778), 1977 (Box 401)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Office management
- An examination of the consequences of using undergraduate grades and GRE scores in the selection of minority doctoral applicants (Reports 009779), 1977 (Box 401)
- Excerpts for meeting of those preparing papers for trustees planning project (Reports 009780), 1976 (Box 401)
  Education and Research/Higher Education & Research; Education and Research/Higher Education and Research
- Final report on the City University of New York: facilities, finance and governance (Reports 009781), 1978 (Box 402)
- The Ford Foundation and the Atlanta University Center (Reports 009782), 1977 (Box 402)
  African American universities and colleges; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States
- Ford Foundation program for major grants to selected black colleges (Reports 009783), 1974 (Box 402)
  African American universities and colleges -- Finance; African Americans -- Education, Higher; Universities and colleges -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States
- Freeing the "stuck" and aiding the terminated: expanding the career horizons of tenured college professors (Reports 009784), 1980 (Box 402)
  89 p.
- Future program: education and research (Reports 009785), 1975 (Box 402)
  An information paper for the Education Committee of the Trustees.
- Graduate fellowships for minority students (Reports 009786), 1971 (Box 402)
  Minorities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Minorities -- Education, Higher; Education, Higher
- HE and R program status report (Reports 009787), 1977 (Box 402)
- Higher Education and Research Venture Fund Program (Reports 009788), 1972 (Box 402)
  Request for eight grants of appropriation.
  53 p. + attachments.
  Education, Higher -- Finance
- Interim report on the expanded Women's Program final version (Reports 009790), 1981 (Box 402)
  18 p., tables -- 28 cm.
  Women -- Services for -- Endowments; Women -- United States -- Endowments
- The issue before the court: Who gets ahead in America? (Reports 009791-001), 1977; Bundy, McGeorge (1919-1996) (Box 402)
  Discusses The Regents of the University of California v. Allan Bakke prior to the ruling.'The case revolves around one white man's claim t hat he was discriminated against in favor of blacks, but far more is at stake in the deliberations now getting under
  37 p.
  Minorities -- Education; Discrimination in education -- Law and legislation; Reverse discrimination -- Law and legislation
- The issues before the court: who gets ahead in America? Nov. (Reports 009791-002), 1977
  'The case revolves around one white man's claim that he was discriminated against in favor of blacks, but far more is at stake in the deliberations now getting under way before the Supreme Court of the United States. Is America ever really going to be the
  Atlantic online
  Affirmative action programs -- Law and legislation; Education, Higher; Minorities -- Education; Bakke, Allan Paul -- Trials, litigation, etc.
- March 29th discussion of initial plans for a Foundation conference on the Bakke case and affirmative action in education (Reports 009792), 1977 (Box 402)
  Education, Higher; Minorities -- Education; Affirmative action programs in education
- Memorandum for participants in May 4-5 meeting at the Ford Foundation regarding the under-representation of minorities in higher education (Reports 009793), 1977 (Box 402)
  20 p. + attachments.
- Minority admissions and performance in graduate study: A preliminary study of fellowship programs of the Ford Foundation and the Danforth Foundation (Reports 009794), 1977 (Box 402)
- Six-month report on the Women's Program DAP (Reports 009795), 1981 (Box 402)
  Women -- Services for -- Ford Foundation
- A preliminary evaluation: the Ford Foundation-American Institute of Architects scholarship program (Reports 009796), 1975 (Box 402)
  Education, Higher; Minorities -- Education, Higher
- Program evaluation: Education and Research Division (Reports 009797), 1976 (Box 402)
  An information paper for the Education Committee of the Ford Foundation Trustees.
  6 p. + attachement.
- Program support of selected black colleges in the Higher Education an Minority Affairs Program (Reports 009798), 1977 (Box 402)
- Progress report of PPSO task force on the military and society (Reports 009799), 1980 (Box 402)
  Education and Public Policy (EPP)/Public Policy and Social Organization; Education and Public Policy (EPP)/Public Policy and Social Organization
  Public policy and social organization; Military service
- Rope production by village women (Reports 009800), undated (Box 402)
  Women -- India; Artisans -- India
- Six who wanted to -- enough (Reports 009801), undated (Box 402)
  A report regarding college recruitment of minority students.
- Summary of conference on strengthening graduate education and increasing the opportunity for American minorities (Reports 009802), 1977 (Box 402)
  Minorities -- Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Graduate work; Education, Higher -- United States
- The third minority: Ford Foundation assistance to Puerto Ricans (Reports 009803), 1975 (Box 402)
  Economic assistance -- Puerto Rico; Endowments -- Puerto Rico -- Evaluation
- Notes toward a study of the Latin American university (Reports 009804), 1967 (Box 402)
  Universities and colleges -- Latin America; Education, Higher -- Research -- Latin America
- Overseas compensation study (Reports 009805), 1969 (Box 402)
  7 p. + attachments: tables, graphs -- 28 cm.
  Employment in foreign countries; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration
- Summaries of Ford Foundation in Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Peru, Uruguay and Venezuela (Reports 009806), 1968 (Box 402)
  Briefs prepared for President Bundy on eve of his trip to Latin America in Jan. 1969.
  Ford Foundation programs -- Latin America
- Middle East and North Africa Review Conference, June 20-21, 1972: conference objectives and procedures (Reports 009807) (Box 402)
  L72-236.
  12 p. + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Charity organization -- Middle East; Charity organization -- Africa, North; Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa, North
- The Ford Foundation Review Conference on the Middle East and North Africa, June 20-21 (Reports 009808), 1972 (Box 402)
  7 p. + attachments: principally tables, maps, charts -- 28 cm.
- Human resources: quantitative and qualitative aspects (Reports 009809), 1972 (Box 402)
  Paper for Ford Foundation Review Conference on the Middle East and North Africa.
  PAPER Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
  Population -- Middle East; Population -- Africa, North
- Strengthening sustainable forest management and livelihoods to build community assets and protect upland areas and strengthening sustainable grassland management and livelihoods to build community assets and protect arid areas (POM), January 26, 2006 / (Reports 009810) (Box 402)
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Community and Resource Development
  18, 18 p. (irregular pagination), tables, maps -- 28 cm.
  Program Officer Memo; POM
  Sustainable development -- China; Economic development -- Environmental aspects -- China; Forestry and community -- China; Natural resources -- China -- Management; Grassland conservation -- China
- Implications for Foundation strategy of the Rand study on economic development and population growth in the Middle East (Reports 009811), 1972 (Box 402)
  50 p. -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Research -- Middle East; Population assistance -- Middle East
- Management development in Turkey: 1952 (Reports 009812), 1972 (Box 403)
  L72-236
  25 p. -- 28 cm.
  Industrial management -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Turkey; Executives -- Training of -- Turkey; Executives -- Supply and demand -- Turkey
- The Foundation program in the Middle East (Reports 009813), 1972 (Box 403)
- MEA and population growth in the Middle East and North Africa: 1963-1972 (Reports 009814) (Box 403)
  International Division/Middle East and Africa; International Division/Middle East and Africa
  23 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Birth control -- Africa, North; Birth control -- Middle East; Endowments -- Africa, North -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation
- The Palestine problem and the development process in the Middle East (Reports 009815), 1972 (Box 403)
  27 p. -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Palestine
- Middle Eastern oil and the western world: prospects and problems (Reports 009816), 1972 (Box 403)
  23 p.: table -- 28 cm.
  Petroleum industry and trade -- Middle East; Petroleum industry and trade -- Africa, North; Petroleum reserves -- United States
- Development opportunities in North Africa and the Middle East and the role of the World Bank Group (Reports 009818), 1972 (Box 403)
  Paper from Ford Foundation Review Conference on the Middle East and North Africa.
  22 leaves + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Africa, North; Economic development -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa, North; Technical assistance -- Middle East; World Bank Group; International Division Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N
- The Saudi Arabian experience: a cooperative effort for achieving development (Reports 009819), 1972 (Box 403)
  25 leaves + attachments: charts -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Saudi Arabia
- North Africa: Background: New York University (Reports 009820), 1972 (Box 403)
  Natural resources -- Africa, North
- Agricultural resources and agricultural peoples of the Middle East: past, present, and future (Reports 009821), 1972 (Box 403)
  Agriculture -- Middle East
- Problems in the realization of development potentials (Reports 009822), 1972 (Box 403)
  24 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Middle East; Central planning -- Middle East
- The special case of Israel (Reports 009823), 1972 (Box 403)
  17 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Endowments -- Israel -- Evaluation; Technical assistance -- Israel; International relations
- The Foundation's Middle East program: 1958-1963 (Reports 009824), 1972 (Box 403)
  6 p. -- 28 cm.
- Beginnings of the Foundation's program in North Africa (Reports 009825), 1972 (Box 403)
  14 p. -- 28 cm.
  Charity organization -- Africa, North; Technical assistance -- Africa, North
- Hill to Hall on the art of giving money away (Reports 009826), 1972 (Box 403)
  Letter to Harvey Hall, dated March 1, 1972.
  10 p. -- 28 cm.
  Letter on the art of giving money away ...
  Economic assistance -- Developing countries; Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Charity organization -- Developing countries
- The Ford Foundation in the Middle East and North Africa, 1952-1971 draft (Reports 009827), 1972 (Box 403)
  Background on the Middle East and North Africa and Foundation activities in the region.
  85 p. -- 28 cm.
  Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa, North; Middle East -- Endowments
- Research, scholarship, and cultural development October 1971. (Reports 009828) (Box 403)
  Notes from Education Session, International Division Conference, New Delhi, October 25-29, 1971.
  L71-23.
  18 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Cultural property -- Protection -- Developing countries; Social sciences -- Research -- Developing countries
- Resource management and environmental problems in Southeast Asia (Reports 009829), 1971 (Box 403)
  64 p. -- 28 cm.
  Environmental management -- Southeast Asia; Natural resources -- Southeast Asia -- Management
- The Ford Foundation's program in India, Nepal, and Ceylon (Reports 009830-001), 1971 (Box 403)
  This paper is included in "The Ford Foundation International Division Conference."
  PAPER Conference (1971 Oct. 25-29: New Delhi, India)
  International Division; PAPER Conference (1971 Oct); Developing countries
- The Ford Foundation International Division Conference: New Delhi, India, October 25-29 (Reports 009830-002), 1971 (Box 403)
  Technical assistance -- India; Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- India; Philanthropy -- Developing countries
- Major conclusions of the International Division discussions, October 14-15 (Reports 009831), 1971 (Box 403)
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation
- A summary statistical review of education in the world (Reports 009832), 1971 (Box 403)
  L71-23
  25 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Series A: situation no. 1
  Education -- Statistics; Education -- Research
- International Division Conference, New Delhi, Thursday, October 28, 1971: education, January 1972. (Reports 009833) (Box 403)
  Discussion of where to direct Foundation support to other countries.
  International Division; India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Philanthropy -- Developing countries
- Should Eastern Europe be considered as a less-developed area? (Reports 009834), 1971 (Box 403)
  Technical assistance -- Europe, Eastern; Endowments -- Europe, Eastern -- Evaluation
- Management issues and the family planning programs of Korea, Taiwan and Malaysia: problems and opportunities for linkages to local management resources: a trip report, March 27 - April 12 (Reports 009835), 1972 (Box 403)
  L72-173.
  PAPER Conference (1972 June 12-16: Helsingr, Denmark)
- Summary of argument: education and training for public policymaking: a program strategy paper for the Ford Foundation (Reports 009836), 1972 (Box 403)
  L72-173
  13 p. -- 28 cm
  Public administration -- United States; Professional employees in government -- United States; Government productivity -- United States
- Management and population programs: Report of a visit to Thailand and the Philippines (Reports 009837), 1972 (Box 403)
  PAPER Conference (1972 June 12-15: Helsingr, Denmark)
- Market and marketing research in family planning (Reports 009838), 1972 (Box 403)
- Management problems of the family planning and population program in Egypt (Reports 009839), 1965 (Box 403)
- Systems analysis in family planning programming: Carnegie-Mellon University (Reports 009840), 1972 (Box 403)
- The use of cases and other teaching tools to improve family planning program management (Reports 009841), 1972 (Box 403)
- The role of institutes of public administration in population and family planning programs (Reports 009842), 1971 (Box 404)
  62 p.
- Excerpts from population program assistance (Reports 009843), 1971 (Box 404)
- Program evaluation as a management tool: both technology and a state of mind (Reports 009844), 1972 (Box 404)
- Administrative concerns in family planning in six developing countries (Reports 009845), 1971 (Box 404)
- The planning-operation-evaluation cycle in family planning program administration: a management problem (Reports 009846), 1972 (Box 404)
- Management problems of family planning and population programs: observations by Foundation staff and consultants (Reports 009847), 1972 (Box 404)
- Excerpts from tentative work plan: a forward look at the strategy, role and financial requirements of UNFPA (Reports 009848), 1972 (Box 404)
  *United Nations Fund for Population Activities.
- Management and family planning (Reports 009849), 1972 (Box 404)
- Report on family planning management improvement in Central America and Mexico (Reports 009850), 1972 (Box 404)
- The Ford Foundation and "population management" in Turkey (Reports 009851), 1972 (Box 404)
  International Division/Population Program; International Division/Population Program
  10 leaves + appendices -- 28 cm.
  Population research -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Turkey; Birth control -- Turkey
- The ernakulam vasectomy campaigns: Michigan State University (Reports 009852), 1972 (Box 404)
  This is chapter two of book entitled, Field experiments on family planning incentives.
  Vasectomy; Population; Birth control
- Management problems of family planning programs in the Philippines (Reports 009853), 1972 (Box 404)
  Population -- Philippines -- Congresses
- Management of family planning in India: a critique (Reports 009854), 1972 (Box 404)
  20 p. + appendices.
- The administration of family planning programs (Reports 009855), 1972 (Box 404)
- Summary of findings of the resources for the future study for the Commission on Population Growth and the American Future. (Reports 009856), 1972 (Box 404)
- Woman's new economic commandments (Reports 009857), 1972 (Box 404)
- Scope and function of a population planning unit (Reports 009858), 1972 (Box 404)
- Effect of population change on the attainment of educational goals in the developing countries (Reports 009859), 1971 (Box 404)
- Population as a social science problem (Reports 009860), 1972 (Box 404)
- The Population Council's International Committee for Contraception Research (Reports 009861), 1972 (Box 404)
- Foundation support of training in reproductive biology (Reports 009862), 1972 (Box 404)
- Recent developments in contraceptive research (Reports 009863), 1972 (Box 404)
- Foundation support of reproductive biology: new directions for the 70's? (Reports 009864), 1972 (Box 404)
- Other issues: a view from India (Reports 009865), 1972 (Box 404)
  Foundation strategy for population work in the 70s: III
- Relevant activities of other donor agencies in the social sciences in Latin America (Reports 009866), 1972 (Box 404)
  Population -- Research
- Report for Elsinore session on social science (Reports 009867), 1972 (Box 404)
- Population related social science research in the Middle East and Africa status report: (Reports 009868), 1972 (Box 404)
  Population research -- Middle East; Population research -- Africa
- Status report on Latin America: comparative social research on problems relevant to population policy (Reports 009869), 1972 (Box 404)
  9 p. + attachement.
- Issues in introducing into the school system education approaches to population problems: viewed for the perspective of the educational community: the case of Peru (Reports 009870), 1972 (Box 404)
- The Philippine population education program and its antecedents (Reports 009871), 1972 (Box 404)
- Letter to Robert S. Wickham (Reports 009872), 1972 (Box 404)
- In-school sex education, family life education and population education in Colombia: a case study in the future tense (Reports 009873), 1972 (Box 404)
- A case study on the development of school population education: the Tjikini Foundation School in Indonesia (Reports 009874), 1972 (Box 404)
- Population education in the schools: status and needs (Reports 009875), 1972 (Box 404)
- Issues and problems in introducing population education (Reports 009876), 1971 (Box 404)
- Toward population education in Tunisia (Reports 009877), 1972 (Box 404)
- A brief note about BEMFAM's national planning seminars (Reports 009878), 1972 (Box 404)
  Population -- Brazil
- Population education in India: a case study (Reports 009879), 1972 (Box 404)
- The Athoor experience: implications for a statewide family planning program (Reports 009880), 1972 (Box 404)
  Includes, "On the family program in India with special reference to Ghandigram", by Philip M. Hauser, University of Chicago, May 1970.
  21 p. + attachment.
- Variables affecting the population policies of West African governments (Reports 009881), 1972 (Box 404)
- Report of the President: the difficulty of being earnest (Reports 009882), 1971 (Box 405)
  This article is the Population Council's Annual Report, 1970.
- Establishing a balance between family planning services and communications activities (Reports 009883), 1972 (Box 405)
  Population -- Brazil; Birth control -- Brazil